100th Regiment, New York Volunteers Veteran Association Records
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
100th Regiment, New York Volunteers Veteran Association Records
1894 - 1953
1911 - 1951
3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 100th (1862-1865)
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
100th Regiment Veterans Association; gift; 1956/10/14.
contracts; Corbett, Inis L.; military commissions; muster rolls; Nichols, Edwin; Porter, Peter A. (Peter Augustus), 1853-1925; United States History Civil War, 1861-1865
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
The 100th New York Regiment broke camp at Fort Porter in 1862 to join the Army of the Potomac in the Civil War; it originally numbered approximately 1,000 men. The regiment reunited annually, often together with Peter A. Porter's 8th N.Y. Heavy Artillery regiment.
Includes minutes from annual reunions (1911-1951); general membership records and correspondence kept by the secretary; some materials related to veterans of 8th N.Y. Heavy Artillery Regiment; clippings related to the organization's activities; and official documents, including a muster roll (Co. B, 1865) and appointment of Edwin Nichols as Captain, 1864.
Organized into seven series:
I. Correspondence, notes and records.
II. Minutes from annual reunions.
III. Printed materials.
IV. Death register.
V. Account book.
VI. Photographs.
VII. Other official documents.
- I. Correspondence, notes and records, 1930 - 1937
  - A. General (Box-folder 1.1-1.5)
  - B. Membership records (Box-folder 1.6)
  - C. Correspondence, 1930 - 1937 (Box-folder 1.7-1.8)
- II. Minutes from Annual Reunions, 1911 - 1921
  - Minutes undated (1.9-1.10)
  - Minutes, 1911-1927 (bound volume) (Folder Vol.)
  - Minutes, 1926 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Minutes, 1929, 43rd Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Minutes, [1930], 44th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Minutes, 1931, 45th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Minutes, 1932, 46th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Minutes, 1933, 47th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Minutes, [1934]. 48th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Minutes, 1935-36, 49th and 50th Annual reunion, 1935 - 1936 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Minutes, 1937-1941, 51st-55th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Minutes, 1937, 51st Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.9A)
  - Minutes, 1938, 52nd Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Minutes, 1939, 53rd Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Minutes, 1940, 54th Annual reunion (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Minutes, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1942 - 1944 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Minutes, 1945 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Minutes, 1946, 1948, 1949, 1951, 1946 - 1951 (Box-folder 3.3)
- III. Printed matter
  - General (Box-folder 3.4-3.5)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 3.6)
- IV. Death register (Box-folder 3.7)
- V. Account book, 1937 - 1953 (Box-folder 3.8)
- VI. Photographs (Box-folder 3.9)
- VII. Other official documents (Box-folder 3.10)